<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bubu on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://free2dots.github.io/tags/bubu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bubu on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 12:57:38 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://free2dots.github.io/tags/bubu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mytest - oo</title>
      <link>https://free2dots.github.io/posts/mytest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 12:57:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://free2dots.github.io/posts/mytest/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;h1 id=&#34;mods&#34;&gt;Mods&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In school writing essays is almost exclusive related to/and about English literature.
Topics like: &lt;em&gt;symbolism in Dickens&lt;/em&gt;, rather than &lt;em&gt;the role of color in fashion&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This was due, according to Graham, to how the writing and the literature were introduced in high school (of course he talks about American educational system).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regardless of its origin, the output of the unification of literature and composition is asking students to imitate what English professors have published in journals years before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;no-defense&#34;&gt;No defense&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Despite school essays, the real essays do not need to take a position and defend it (to my knowledge, in the Italian education you do not have to defend your position, usually you are asked to provide a kind of overview).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This feature originated from medieval universities, where scholars were advocates, train to take side of an argument.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The problem with this approach is that you cannot change question to seek the truth, since your goal is to win&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In this framework, the topic is chosen in advanced (&lt;strong&gt;it is your thesis&lt;/strong&gt;), the paragraphs have to support the initial idea and the conclusions are the first statement rephrased.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good writing requires right answers rather than right arguing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In his drafts P.G. wants to know:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the boring parts (that he will cut)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the unconvincing bits (that we&amp;rsquo;ll be further elaborated but not better argued)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For smart readers, convincing arguments and true arguments become identical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;trying&#34;&gt;Trying&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Essay derives from the French &lt;em&gt;essayer&lt;/em&gt;, to try (see [[Michel de Montaigne]]&amp;rsquo;s book of &lt;em&gt;essais&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;essai&lt;/em&gt; is then an &lt;strong&gt;attempt&lt;/strong&gt; (In Italian, &lt;em&gt;saggio&lt;/em&gt; in the meaning of test to something, it derived from &lt;em&gt;exigere&lt;/em&gt;, to examine. To not be confused with &lt;em&gt;saggio/wise&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An essay is something you write to try to figure something out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you do not have a thesis, but a question!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Montaigne&amp;rsquo;s discovery: Expressing ideas help to form them. Most of P.G. ideas come while he is writing. ==I can related to this feeling. Probably in the act of writing you manage to focus on the task and are able to shape thoughts in a way that opens new possibilities. It happened to me while writing my PhD thesis: wonderful ideas on how to improve things or to check something else. As said in the [[Kurzgesagt]]&amp;rsquo;s video [[A tail end]], while doing things you navigate life without many questions, you try to float.==&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In an essay you are writing for yourself, you are thinking out loud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The presence of an audience forces you to think well (like cleaning the house if you have guests)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-river&#34;&gt;The river&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An essay needs also &lt;strong&gt;answer&lt;/strong&gt;. If the starting question leads to a dead end, you do not publish the &lt;em&gt;essay&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Tell the reader something he did not already know&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; is not important as long as it is interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are searching the truth not defending a position. Like a river, your path is longer than a straight line but it is the most economical route to the sea (in terms of potential(?) energy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Algorithm of the river, for the writer: at each step &lt;strong&gt;flow down == flow interesting&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;of all next places, choose the most interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;from paragraph to paragraph, follow the ideas as they flow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you hit a wall, backtrack and restart from an earlier point&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An essay is not a reference work. Better to be interesting and unespected, than on a prescribed track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;surprise&#34;&gt;Surprise&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Essays should aim for maximum surprise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for something you did not know, and that contradicts what you thought you know, i.e. &lt;strong&gt;surprises&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finding such surprising is half of the work. You should find something you thought a lot and still surprises you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Features:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;topic you thought a lot about&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ability to ferret out the inexpected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;observation&#34;&gt;Observation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;how do you learn how to &lt;strong&gt;ferret out&lt;/strong&gt; the unexpected? Creating connections between different things. The more anomalies you have seen, better you are at discovering new ones. ==It makes me think about [[Mr. Rip]] live onf critical thinking, when he mentioned==&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;==Literacy of any sort gives you the power to recognize and unambigously label things that the illiterate can easily ignore as noise, fadd and bulshit.==&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;==from the [[Gervais Principle]]==&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habits to improve the odd of finding surprises:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;habit of asking questions, maily starting with &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to discern among different why&amp;rsquo;s, prioritize what seems &lt;strong&gt;wrong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;among things that seems wrong, find the &lt;strong&gt;humorous&lt;/strong&gt; ones, &lt;em&gt;surprises makes us laugh&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;write down what surprises you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you take yourself too seriously, you will avoid situations where your inexperience makes you look foolish. Doing so does not make you find surprises.
this is a text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;lol&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
